Office of the Vice President for Arts, Sciences, and Technology Records UA061
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office of the Vice President for Arts, Sciences, and Technology Records
1992 -- 1998
1987 -- 2003
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Bernstein, Melvin
Office of the Vice President for Arts, Sciences and Technology
UA061
2.9 Linear Feet 3 boxes
2 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
The collection is organized into five series: Policy Council files; Task Force on Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Life files; Appointment calendars; the Higher Education Initiative; and Annual Reports.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes meeting minutes, correspondence, memos, reports, audio tapes and documents pertaining to committee work and retreats, statistics on budget, faculty and students, appointment books, two CDs of the HEI website, and a paperweight.
Biographical / Historical
The Office of the Vice President for Arts, Sciences and Technology (also known as the Vice President for Arts, Sciences and Engineering) was established in the fall of 1986 and ceased to exist in 2001. Various deans, including the Dean of Liberal Arts and Jackson, the Dean of the School of Engineering, and the Dean of the Graduate School of Art and Sciences, reported to the VP for A, S & T. The Office of the VP for A, S & T influenced a broad range of academic policies through its Policy Council, an executive group of administrative and academic deans in Arts & Sciences. The Vice President for Arts, Sciences and Technology (VP for A, S & T) reported to the University Provost and Senior Vice President. The activities of this high-level administrative office included: strategic planning for student, faculty and program development; addressing issues of diversity and the quality of intellectual life at Tufts; developing new offices to handle ever changing academic and organizational issues; spearheading initiatives such as the Higher Education Initiative (HEI); creating and overseeing task forces, such as the Task Force on Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Life.
Conditions Governing Access
All records in this collection are closed for 75 years.
Administration and Governance -- Planning, evaluation, policies & procedures
- Policy Council Files, 1987 -- 1998; 1992 -- 1998; UA061.001; 2.9 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records of the Policy Council, an executive group of administrative and academic deans in Arts & Sciences: meeting minutes (1992-1998), files pertaining to diversity issues, records and tapes from Policy Council retreats, and statistical data.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically within Council issues.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Policy Council, January 5, 1992; UA061.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, August 31, 1992; UA061.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 5, 1992; UA061.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 11, 1992; UA061.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 2, 1992; UA061.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 16, 1992; UA061.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 26, 1992; UA061.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 3, 1992; UA061.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 13, 1992; UA061.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, December 4, 1992; UA061.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, December 18, 1992; UA061.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, January 22, 1993; UA061.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, February 5, 1993; UA061.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, February 22, 1993; UA061.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, March 3, 1993; UA061.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, March 19, 1993; UA061.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, April 2, 1993; UA061.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, April 9, 1993; UA061.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, April 23, 1993; UA061.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, May 7, 1993; UA061.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, May 28, 1993; UA061.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 7, 1993; UA061.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 14, 1993; UA061.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 23, 1993; UA061.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 28, 1993; UA061.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 29, 1993; UA061.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 8, 1993; UA061.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 14, 1993; UA061.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 22, 1993; UA061.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 3, 1993; UA061.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 18, 1993; UA061.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 23, 1993; UA061.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, December 12, 1993; UA061.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, December 16, 1993; UA061.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, January 14, 1994; UA061.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, January 25, 1994; UA061.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, February 10, 1994; UA061.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, February 24, 1994; UA061.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, March 10, 1994; UA061.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, March 24, 1994; UA061.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, April 7, 1994; UA061.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, May 5, 1994; UA061.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, July 26, 1994; UA061.001.001.00043 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, July 29, 1994; UA061.001.001.00044 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, August 8, 1994; UA061.001.001.00045 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, August 15, 1994; UA061.001.001.00046 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 7, 1994; UA061.001.001.00047 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 21, 1994; UA061.001.001.00048 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 12, 1994; UA061.001.001.00049 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 24, 1994; UA061.001.001.00050 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 9, 1994; UA061.001.001.00051 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 23, 1994; UA061.001.001.00052 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, December 7, 1994; UA061.001.001.00053 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, December 21, 1994; UA061.001.001.00054 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, January 25, 1995; UA061.001.001.00055 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, February 8, 1995; UA061.001.001.00056 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, February 22, 1995; UA061.001.001.00057 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, March 8, 1995; UA061.001.001.00058 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, March 29, 1995; UA061.001.001.00059 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, April 12, 1995; UA061.001.001.00060 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, April 26, 1995; UA061.001.001.00061 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, May 24, 1995; UA061.001.001.00062 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, June 7, 1995; UA061.001.001.00063 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, August 28, 1995; UA061.001.001.00064 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 13, 1995; UA061.001.001.00065 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 27, 1995; UA061.001.001.00066 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 11, 1995; UA061.001.001.00067 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 25, 1995; UA061.001.001.00068 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 8, 1995; UA061.001.001.00069 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, December 6, 1995; UA061.001.001.00070 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, December 20, 1995; UA061.001.001.00071 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, January 17, 1996; UA061.001.001.00072 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, February 28, 1996; UA061.001.001.00073 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, March 13, 1996; UA061.001.001.00074 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, March 27, 1996; UA061.001.001.00075 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, April 10, 1996; UA061.001.001.00076 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, April 24, 1996; UA061.001.001.00077 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, May 8, 1996; UA061.001.001.00078 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, May 21, 1996; UA061.001.001.00079 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, June 3, 1996; UA061.001.001.00080 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 4, 1996; UA061.001.001.00081 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 16, 1996; UA061.001.001.00082 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 2, 1996; UA061.001.001.00083 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 16, 1996; UA061.001.001.00084 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 30, 1996; UA061.001.001.00085 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 12, 1996; UA061.001.001.00086 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 20, 1996; UA061.001.001.00087 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, December 11, 1996; UA061.001.001.00088 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, December 18, 1996; UA061.001.001.00089 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, January 8, 1997; UA061.001.001.00090 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, February 12, 1997; UA061.001.001.00091 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, February 26, 1997; UA061.001.001.00092 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, March 12, 1997; UA061.001.001.00093 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, April 9, 1997; UA061.001.001.00094 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, April 23, 1997; UA061.001.001.00095 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, May 7, 1997; UA061.001.001.00096 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, May 21, 1997; UA061.001.001.00097 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, June 4, 1997; UA061.001.001.00098 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, June 18, 1997; UA061.001.001.00099 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 3, 1997; UA061.001.001.00100 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 17, 1997; UA061.001.001.00101 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, September 25, 1997; UA061.001.001.00102 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 1, 1997; UA061.001.001.00103 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 15, 1997; UA061.001.001.00104 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, October 28, 1997; UA061.001.001.00105 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 12, 1997; UA061.001.001.00106 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 18, 1997; UA061.001.001.00107 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, November 26, 1997; UA061.001.001.00108 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, January 21, 1998; UA061.001.001.00109 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, February 5, 1998; UA061.001.001.00110 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, February 19, 1998; UA061.001.001.00111 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, March 5, 1998; UA061.001.001.00112 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, March 10, 1998; UA061.001.001.00113 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, April 23, 1998; UA061.001.001.00114 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council, May 7, 1998; UA061.001.001.00115 (Box 1)
  - Policy Council Diversity Issues, November 20, 1992; UA061.001.002.00001 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Diversity Issues, May 20, 1993; UA061.001.002.00002 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Diversity Issues, April 12, 1994; UA061.001.002.00003 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Diversity Issues, July 11-12, 1994; UA061.001.002.00004 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Diversity Issues, July 29, 1994; UA061.001.002.00005 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Diversity Issues, September 21, 1994; UA061.001.002.00006 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Diversity Issues, November 21, 1994; UA061.001.002.00007 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Diversity Issues, December 15, 1994; UA061.001.002.00008 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Retreat, 1991; UA061.001.002.00010 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Retreat, 1992; UA061.001.002.00011 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Retreat, 1993; UA061.001.002.00012 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Retreat, 1994; UA061.001.002.00013 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Retreat, 1995; UA061.001.002.00014 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Retreat, 1996; UA061.001.002.00015 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Retreat, Notes and Tapes, 1997; UA061.001.002.00016 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Faculty Data, Retirement, Contacts etc., 1987 -- 1991; UA061.001.002.00017 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Salary Data, 1988 -- 1991; UA061.001.002.00018 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Demographics Data, 1988 -- 1991; UA061.001.002.00019 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Student Data, 1990; UA061.001.002.00020 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Budget Data, February 5, 1998; UA061.001.002.00021 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Policy Council Retreat, June 21, 1997, 1 of 4, UA061.001.003.00001 (Case UA061 Shared 2)
    "Certron" 90 min. instant start dictation cassette
    audiocassette
  - Policy Council Retreat, June 21, 1997, 2 of 4, UA061.001.003.00002 (Case UA061 Shared 2)
  - Policy Council Retreat, June 21, 1997, 3 of 4, UA061.001.003.00003 (Case UA061 Shared 2)
  - Policy Council Retreat, June 21, 1997, 4 of 4, UA061.001.003.00004 (Case UA061 Shared 2)
  - Policy Council Retreat, June 26-27, 1997, 1 of 4, UA061.001.003.00005 (Case UA061 Shared 2)
  - Policy Council Retreat, June 26-27, 1997, 2 of 4, UA061.001.003.00006 (Case UA061 Shared 2)
  - Policy Council Retreat, June 26-27, 1997, 3 of 4, UA061.001.003.00007 (Case UA061 Shared 2)
  - Policy Council Retreat, June 26-27, 1997, 4 of 4, UA061.001.003.00008 (Case UA061 Shared 2)
- Task Force on Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Life Files, 1991 -- 1993; UA061.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains files of the Task Force on Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Life, including minutes and its published report as well as material from the Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Caucus (a LGB faculty and staff group). The Task Force was created by Mel Bernstein at the request of members of the Tufts LGB faculty and staff group. Some of the files are restricted for 70 years because they may contain personal information.
  This series is not arranged.
  75 years from the date of creation. Open for research.
  - [Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual] Caucus, Tufts, 1991 -- 1993; UA061.002.002.00022 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
    75 years from the date of creation.
  - Task Force Report, 1993; UA061.002.002.00023 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Task Force Minutes, 1992 -- 1993; UA061.002.002.00024 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
- Appointment Calendars, 2000 -- 2003; UA061.003; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series consists of bound appointment calendars for the years 2000, 2001, and 2003. The appointment books from 2000 and 2001 each span a calendar year, whereas the 2003 calendar covers only the spring term 2003.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Mel Bernstein Appointment Book, 2000; UA061.003.002.00025 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Mel Bernstein Appointment Book, 2001; UA061.003.002.00026 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Appointment Book, 2003; UA061.003.002.00027 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
- Higher Education Initiative, 1997 -- 2003; 1997; UA061.004; 1.7 Linear Feet; 2 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains material related to the Higher Education Initiative (HEI) which carried out Tufts' third comprehensive self-evaluation. Mel Bernstein launched the HEI in 1997, asking faculty committees, student government, and academic administrators about the threats and opportunities facing education at Tufts. The HEI focused primarily on four broad issues: "coherence and connection in the curriculum," "undergraduate and graduate students: community and communication," "faculty development: teaching & research," and "effective collaborative decision making."
  - Higher Education Initiative Paperweight, 1997; UA061.004.002.00030 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Higher Education Initiative Website, 2003; UA061.004.003.00009 (Case UA061 Shared 2)
    CD
  - Higher Education Initiative Website Archive, 2002; UA061.004.003.00010 (Case UA061 Shared 2)
- Annual Reports and material for Annual Reports, 1988 -- 1997; UA061.005; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains material for the Annual Reports from 1988-1997 and select Annual reports for 1992-1994.
  - Material for Annual Reports, 1988 -- 1997; UA061.005.002.00028 (Box UA061 Shared 1)
  - Annual Reports of the VP for A,S &T, 1992 -- 1994; UA061.005.002.00029 (Box UA061 Shared 1)